Gareth Chidgey

AWS Certified Cloud Solutions Architect and DevOps Consultant

Gareth Chidgey

90 Avondale Road Cheadle Heath Stockport SK3 0DA

07849 477 904 gareth@chidgey.me

Introduction

I began my working life as an Officer in the British Army, trained at the Royal Military Academy Sandhurst in leadership, people management and Human Resources. The learnings I gained from this time are still with me over a decade later. Skills such as crisis management, motivation, character building, staff retention, and change management, vital skills when consulting to technical teams large and small.

My main role is that of acting as a technical consultant, helping teams of engineers to move their process, infrastructure and applications into the cloud. I can help with network design, build and security, integration of Infrastructure as a Service components from cloud providers (primarily AWS) through to all scales of technical training on choosing the right tool for the job and how to implement it.

I am a skilled trainer, able to employ a number of techniques to help people learn new technology. I find upskilling the team to be of great benefit all round, and always make it a priority.

I'm highly experienced at designing enterprise level, highly available software architecture, and also very comfortable delivering the tools to a team to maximise their productivity through automation of complex build pipelines and integrations.

Qualifications

In the last couple of years, I have been undergoing a process of formalising my skills through training and certification. I currently hold five AWS certifications including Architect Professional, and am working on attaining two specialisms by the end of 2019 and the DevOps Pro by the end of Q2 2020.

In addition to my technical qualifications, I am training towards TOGAF and intend to certify by the end of Q1 2020. I am also formalising my Agile skills with SAFe Architect certification by the end of Q1 2020 and SAFe Program Consultant by the end of Q2 2020.

Experience

Gareth Chidgey Ltd / Cloud Solutions Architect and DevOps Consultant

May 2012 - Present, VARIOUS SEE BELOW

During this period I have worked in a number of varied roles, most recently as Lead Architect on a Cloud transformation project for Datamatters who are the IT arm of Jenston Group, a mid size UK Insurance Company.

I want to continue doing this kind of work.

Datamatters / Lead Architect

February 2019 - Date, HEYWOOD

Responsible for the greenfield design of a microservice based solution as a replacement for a 35 year old system, I have lead the organisation into the cloud, designed and implemented infrastructure as code, CI/CD and started an extensive training program.

Firebrand Training / AWS Instructor

February 2019 - Date, GLOBAL

I am an AWS instructor for Firebrand, I conduct accelerated learning courses to put 3-18 delegates through to certification in a growing number of certifications. I have also acted as Subject Matter Expert and designed and built the SysOps Admin course. This is a continuing role, with around 8-10 courses per year.

Tyres on the Drive / Lead Architect and DevOps Engineer

October 2018 - February 2019, HOLMES CHAPEL

I was responsible for leading the re-architecture of a dated monolith to a microservice based solution. I designed and implemented infrastructure as code from network through CI/CD to Front End. I acted as Technical SME in an audit by a leading US consultancy prior to them investing a large sum into the business.

Auden Group / Head of Engineering

August 2017 - October 2017, MEDIACITYUK

Building a new Engineering team from scratch I took the team from 3 to 20 in 2 months. At this point a new CTO was appointed, who wanted to take the Tech team in a different direction.

AppLearn / Head of Development

April 2017 - July 2017, July 2017

I implemented Agile methodology, Training and Development and Project Management processes to the development team. Working closely with the CTO to help the team develop the skills required to realise his dream for the application.

The Hut Group / Software Engineering Manager

November 2016 - April 2017, NORTHWICH

Having been promoted into the role three weeks prior to completing probation, I was asked to take over the Checkout Team. Whilst this meant that I was coding less, I remained the lead developer on the Checkout Front End application that I had spearheaded, and conducted significant department wide training in the new technologies.

Due to PCI compliance, I was responsible for code checking every single release and performing QA on the Agile based behavioural tests as well the code level unit tests.

The Hut Group / Technical Lead

August 2016 - November 2016, NORTHWICH

Leading the team in the production of quality Java and JavaScript applications that come together as the checkout functionality for ~220 websites across ~150 countries. The component was the key component that the group had, and couldn't ever go down. So we had to constantly improve the reliability of the code, and the making of mistakes needed to be kept to the minimum.

During this time, I introduced Node.js, React.js, TypeScript and bootstrap into the tech stack, and architected and built the new yet to be released Checkout Front End application allowing for significantly increased responsiveness by the team.

The Hut Group / Contract Senior Developer

March 2016 - August 2016, NORTHWICH

Working on the Content Delivery Team, I worked on a range of Full Stack PHP applications.

Studio Skylab / Contract Lead Developer

March 2014 - March 2016, TRAFFORD PARK

Running a team of ~ 10 Full Stack PHP/ JS developers. Working hands on throughout.

Sony / Contract Lead Developer

MARCH 2013 - FEBRUARY 2014, RUNCORN/HOME

I architected and built a PHP application that connected the Sony PS4 game Driveclub to Facebook and kept the social elements of the game in sync with equivalent Facebook groups.

Education

Royal Military Academy Sandhurst / CIPD (mil)

The Royal Military Academy Sandhurst in Surrey is where all officers in the British Army are trained to take on the responsibilities of leading the soldiers under their command.

It is globally renowned as the foremost training centre for management and leadership in the world, covering relevant non-military skills such as:

- Team and Individual Psychology
- Team Building
- Leadership
- Business Administration
- Public Speaking
- Management Information
- Staff Administration
- Project Management

- Change Management
- Health and Safety

Salford University / Business Studies

I studied business including:

- Accounting
- Economics
- Human Resources
- Marketing
- Statistics and MI
- Business Law
- Professional Development